Now that we had a very detailed look at the web components in general
and stencil.js in detail which helps you building these web components,
let's have a look at how we can actually deploy and publish and share our web components, across
our own projects as well as with other people because that is one core advantage of web components after
all.
We can easily drop them into any other project to add that piece of functionality which we encapsulated
in our web component.
Now for this, we'll build our stencil web components, so we'll generate these native web components and I'll
then show you different ways of using those generated web components in different projects and how to
get them into different projects.