Now let's briefly have a look at that browser support thing again.
If we are on stenciljs.com, we can go to the browser support area and there, we see the current
state of browser support of the web components generated by stencil.
Now as you can tell, all modern browsers except for Edge fully support all features natively, you can
see that in the table down there even better, Edge and Internet Explorer 11 are kind of the problematic browsers,
Edge is almost there,
some features are missing and polyfilled for now,
Bb the time you're watching this, Edge might already support all these things natively,
Internet Explorer will never support them natively though and therefore, I copied my React app onto my
Windows machine and I ran it there, ran npm install first and let's see if that works in Edge and Internet Explorer.
Now in Edge, if you load it there, it should just work,
you shouldn't need to make any adjustments, it should just work there out of the box without any changes
and it works in exactly the same way it works in Chrome, Safari or Firefox,
so there we see these automatic polyfills being loaded and please be aware that they really are only
loaded in that environment.
If you're running the app in a browser that supports a feature natively, let's say the shadow DOM, then
the respective polyfill is not loaded. In the Internet Explorer,
it would not work out of the box because when I'm recording this, two things are not working. For one,
the promise features are not polyfilled correctly.
Now normally they should be because next gen Javascript functionalities are added by stencil too
but we can easily fix that by adding our own polyfill, here I'm just importing it in the index.html file,
you can find a link to that polyfill in the last lecture of this module. And there's one issue after
I added this polyfill,
it generally works but you see the styling for this second component is missing and that is simply missing
because the CSS variables polyfill doesn't seem to be loaded correctly here and at the point of this
recording, this is simply an open bug in the stencil
repository, so it might very well be fixed when you are viewing this.
Please be aware that generally, the components still works though,
just the variable styling is missing. so if you need to support Internet Explorer right now, you either
need to load polyfill for that feature on your own or leave out CSS variables.
But with that, we see that indeed we got web components that run in a broad variety of browsers, covering
the vast majority of the browser landscape and therefore, we got a really awesome feature which is ready
to use right now.