So that is web components and how you can use them.
We now saw how we can build our projects and get that that dist output here, how we can drag and drop
that into a project if we want to import it with script tags like this, how we can alternatively publish
it to npm though to have it published there either publicly or if we have a paid private account, we can
also publish it privately to only share it amongst our different projects or inside of our company and how
we can then install this with npm install into any project that is managed by npm and then make it work,
for example in our Angular app with adjustments to the main.ts file by defining the elements and our
app module by informing Angular about the fact that we're using custom elements. How we can make it in
React alternatively, to be able to use it there too by simply defining the elements in index.js file
after adding them,
for example with npm install and how we can also make our components work by also defining them in a Vue
project here in the main.js file,
so before we mount our root component. If you want to learn more about React, Vue or Angular, definitely
have a look at my dedicated courses,
I got courses on all these projects but now you know how you can use your stencil build web components
in any of these projects.