With all the core basics out of the way, let's dive into building more complex components or one more
complex component in this module. We'll build a modal component,
so like this pop-up, this overlay inside of a page with a nice backdrop behind it where we can pass
our own content into it and which we can also configure,
for example where we can control from outside whether it's shown or not.
We'll also learn how we can dispatch our own events from inside our web component so that we can react
to these custom events outside of it
and we'll see a lot of the features you already learned about in the last modules in action too.
So a great practice as well as many exciting new features,
let's dive in.