Welcome on board of this course, I'm very happy that you joined me in this course because in this course, we'll
dive into a super exciting topic,
we'll dive into web components.
You will learn how to build your own custom HTML elements with features that are already baked into
browsers and into modern Javascript.
You will not need any other third party library or framework,
you will not need Angular or React or JQuery,
you will learn a technology or you will learn about a technology that works as you see it in this course
out of the box. In this course, you will not just learn everything about web components from scratch
and we will write plenty of web components like a modal or a side drawer,
you will not just learn about these features in this course, you will also learn about a tool, stencil.js
that also spits out native web components but makes the development of these way easier even.
So you will learn about the vanilla Javascript web components and then you will learn an even easier
way of developing such components with the help of stencil.js.
And you will learn how to build your own custom elements, like your own custom modal or side drawer,
all things we will build in this course to learn about the different features that make up these custom
elements step-by-step.
So let's dive into the most important question first,
what in detail are web components before I then give you an overview of the course and we then dive deeply
into web components and everything that makes up web components.