This is a totally optional module.
If you're up to date with ES6+ Javascript features like arrow functions, let and const or with general
important Javascript basics like how to work with array and the built-in array methods and things like
that,
then you may absolutely skip this module. In this course,
we'll use both Javascript and later also a bit of Typescript,
you don't need to know Typescript,
no worries
but in both languages so to say, we will use modern Javascript features and therefore, definitely go
through this refresher
if you're not sure if you got all these basics set, if you really are familiar with the latest Javascript
features or at least keep this module in mind so that you can come back to it if you later encounter
some syntax, some Javascript feature
you're just not sure about.
So in this module, I'll briefly walk you through important next generation Javascript features, what they
do, why we use them and how we use them, so that we're all on the same page for the rest of this course.