We learned a lot about classes and arrow functions,
let's now turn our heads towards new operators we'll be able to use in the future of Javascript, the Spread
and the Rest operators.
Actually it's only one operator, three dots and yes, this may look strange but the operator is just three
dots,
now if we call it Spread or Rest depends on where we use it. The Spread operator is used to split up array
elements or object properties,
so we spread up an array or object.
For example if we have an old array and we want to add all the elements from that old array to a new
array and additionally, add a one and a two element, this first syntax would be what we use, three dots in
front of oldArray will simply pull out all the elements and add it to the newArray which we create
with square brackets and also of course then we can add more elements to it
since we just use the normal syntax with square brackets to create an array. The same for the object,
we create a new object with curly braces with the new prop
but then we also have
...oldObject to pull out all the properties of the oldObject and their values and add them as key value
pairs to the new object.
As a side note, if the old object
also had a new property,
it would be overridden by newProp 5 here,
so our own property takes precedence, this is the Spread operator.
Now the Rest operator is the same operator but used differently. Here it's used to merge a list of function
arguments into an array
and this shows us where we use it,
we use it in a function argument list,
here is an example.
sortArgs receives an unlimited amount of arguments,
so one argument, two, three or whatever, with ... we only write one argument, args but we may actually
receive more than one
and they will all be merged together into an array.
So then we can apply array methods to our argument list or do whatever we want to do with our conveniently
stored arguments,
let's have a look at both
usages on
JSBin then.
So let's start with the Spread operator, I'll create an array of numbers,
so one, two, three, add as many as you want.
Now I want to create a new array, newNumbers
and as you saw, Spread is now simply used by adding three dots,
then the oldArray numbers and then potentially, you don't have to do that, new numbers like 4
and again that is optional.
With that if I now console log newNumbers here and I hit run, we get one, two, three, four, the oldArray
with all its elements and the new element
and actually, we don't add the old element,
if we were to do that without the dots, it would be included as one element inside the new element,
it really pulled out the old elements as you can clearly see.
So that's the Spread operator and you will see me use this throughout this course a couple of times on
both arrays and objects to for example conveniently copy arrays or add properties to an object whilst
safely copying that old object.
Again, I will obviously also always mention why I'm using that operator when I do in the course,
just be aware that it exists,
let's now see the same for objects. I'll create a person object here where I have a name,
let's say Max
and now I will have a newPerson object which is a Javascript object, a new one
where I first of all use the Spread operator on person to copy all the property value pairs of the old
object and potentially and that's also optional,
add a new property
and now if I console log newPerson, you may ignore this error which is thrown by JSBin,
the syntax will be supported in our course project,
if we do this, you see object is printed here with name Max and age 28, so it's taking the oldPerson and distributing
it into the newPerson,
that's the Spread operator.
Now the Rest operator which is used less often though is used in a function
and you could of course also use an ES6 arrow function.
So there, we could have a filter function, whatever you want to name it and we get a couple of args and
you don't have to name this args here, you can also name this a or whatever you want
but you have to use the three dots in front of it.
So then there, you can simply return and
we could use the inline syntax here to write it all in one line without the return keyword,
here I'll use return,
you could return args and then let's say we call the built-in filter method which is available on arrays
and keep in mind, the dots here are used as a Rest operator and that merges the arguments into an array,
so we can use array methods like filter. Filter will execute a function on every element in the passed in
array,
so here we would get our element and then we could use an inline arrow function to simply say return
true or false
which filter expects if the element is equal to 1.
Now that might be a lot of syntax you don't know,
three equal signs checks for type and value equality,
so that also has to be a number and this is just an arrow function
we passed to the built-in filter method,
so this has nothing to do with Rest or Spread. With that
we could call filter and let's console log it to see something, console log filter, so our filter function
here on let's say one, two, three and actually, we should only log one here as an array though because we filter
this array which is created with the Rest operator, with the three dots here.
So that's Rest and Spread, again Spread is the usage of the three dots
you'll see more often in this course.