Now
another important topic which is only partly related to next gen Javascript
and you really should already know that
is that Javascript of course is able to handle asynchronous code.
Let's say you are sending an HTTP request from inside your Javascript app,
then there are different solutions like callbacks or promises to handle the response of that asynchronous
task or of this HTTP request without blocking code execution of your code until the response is there.
Now I can only recommend this article to which you find a link attached to this video,
if you want to learn more about async code in Javascript and different solutions to it,
in this course, we'll use promises at a later point of time, so you should be able to understand that and
you also find other resources on that. In case you don't
know promises and you really need to learn it from scratch,
take a look at those resources,
otherwise just take them as a reference in case something is unclear
at a later point of time.