So over the last modules, we had a very close look at all the basics you need to have set to build your
own web components, your own custom HTML elements. And now that we built our first HTML elements and
used a broad variety of features that help us with that,
the obvious question is, how do we get these custom HTML elements we built for us here into the different
projects we might be building or into the projects of other people,
how can we deploy our web component
so to say? Now towards the end of the course, I will have a detailed deployment module where I will show
you things like how to publish your own libraries to npm and what npm is, is something we'll learn
until then.
So a detailed deployment module will come later at the course after we covered stencil because maybe
you already wondered what's this stencil thing which is mentioned in the course title. Well we'll have
a look at it right now and we will understand why it can be helpful,
it is a tool that helps us with building web components
and here is why we might want to use it.