Let's start with deploying, so reusing our web component. This is the modal we built in the last course
module and it works fine here,
now here is Chrome,
it would also work fine in Firefox by the way.
Now how would you reuse it there?
Well that's super simple.
You would use it in exactly the same way you use it here.
You have your web project which will have some HTML pages in the end, be that one HTML page you have
as part of your Angular or React project or be that a server side rendered HTML page, rendered with a
templating engine like Laravel's blade engine or EJS or pug for NodeJS.
So you will have some HTML which is served to your users in the end
and in that HTML page, you'll simply add one script import pointing at your Javascript file here
which contains all your component code
and of course you also need to ship your Javascript file onto the server where your HTML file lives
too.
So then you simply add that script import and you can start using your custom component because that is
exactly what we're doing here
and this is no special development only set up here.
This is a normal HTML page using our normal Javascript file which is served in a normal Chrome browser
and therefore of course, I could also open my index.html file with Firefox for example.
This opens up here and there, I can just click that button and have the same working web component because
the latest version of Firefox just as the latest version of Chrome natively supports the web component
specifications, so custom elements, the shadow DOM and so on. Here on the Mac, I can also try that in Safari.
There I also have my working web component because Safari just like Firefox and Chrome supports web
components.
Now the great exception again of course is the Internet Explorer and Edge but their support is coming
and still, this whole support thing, browser support thing is one of the reasons why stencil.js, a
tool that helps us with building web components, is very appealing.
Let's take a closer look at this browser support thing again.