I already mentioned that you can google for can I use and then custom elements or shadow DOM and you
should find a search result from caniuse.com, here for shadow DOM V1 and if we inspect this,
we see Firefox is great,
Chrome is great,
Safari has partial support but that is getting better
but Edge and Internet Explorer is not that great.
If you search for web components browser support instead of can I use, then you'll find this webcomponents.org
and on that page if you scroll down, you indeed find this browser support table which clearly
shows us that Edge and Internet Explorer is not even mentioned here
does not natively support all these features yet,
custom elements in the shadow DOM need to be polyfilled there.
Now in case you don't know what that is, a polyfill is basically an extra script file you import which
then basically adds certain features, rebuilds certain features in the browser,
it's obviously seldom as good as the official implementation but at least, it gets your project, your
web component working. And on webcomponents.org,
you actually find that polyfills section which you can click where you can find detailed instructions
on what you need to install and how you can get started with polyfills to make your web components
work in Internet Explorer and Edge too and definitely read through that resource
if you want to make your web component as we built it here
work in Edge and in Internet Explorer. To be precise,
you will find
a lecture after this one where I give you some starting hints on how you can make this component work
there.
However it's not really worth the effort because stencil.js, this tool into which we'll dive in a second
will make his whole deployment and distribution process way easier and will ensure that our web components
work in all major browsers out of the box without us needing to do any special extra setup. So that will
be awesome
and that is one reason why we dive into stencil. To see the other reason as well,
let's create a new stencil project.