To use stencil.js, we need to download NodeJS from nodejs.org.
Now we will not write any NodeJS
code, NodeJS
is a Javascript runtime which allows you to write Javascript server side code.
We will not write any of that but NodeJS is used behind the scenes by stencil which is a build tool
for web components in the end,
it runs some scripts that are using NodeJS features to basically give us a way of creating web components
that is more convenient and then compile that code to native web component code and NodeJS
also installs with another package, the npm, the Node Package Manager, a tool which allows us to install
tools and dependencies of tools on our machine and inside of projects and stencil will be such a tool installed
through npm.
So your first step is to simply install the latest version of NodeJS,
in my case 11.2 but pick whatever latest version you have,
click on this,
it works on all operating systems,
it should automatically select your operating system here and you can simply walk through the installer
this download gives you to then install NodeJS and npm on your machine.
Once you did install NodeJS, you should have npm installed,
so you should now be able to run the npm command here and we'll use this command to create a new stencil
project,
you don't need to install anything else, it will all be installed on the fly.
First of all, navigate into a folder where you want to create that new project and with project, I mean
a project which we will use to build web components which we then can use in any other project.
So here I already navigated into such a folder and now you can run npm init and then stencil and if
you hit enter, it will automatically install stencil on the fly and then you will see this prompt here and
there, you should choose component to create a new project used for building web components.
You can also build whole applications with stencil,
this simply means that you build multiple web components that work together to build an entire app
but here, we'll just build a component library which not necessarily gives us a front-end web app but a
collection of components we can use anywhere.
Hit enter there and give your project a name, I'll name it web-components-stencil
but you can choose any name you want,
confirm this with a Y and thereafter, navigate into this newly created,
in my case, web components stencil folder.
Now you can run npm start to start a simple development server which spins up an index.html file that
loads a default web component which gets created out of the box
but here, let's simply open that project in our IDE first of all to see what we get there and how
building web components with stencil looks like.