For this, I'm using Visual Studio Code
and I opened this web components stencil folder recreated and this is how it looks like. It obviously
has more files than our old project
and this is because stencil again is a tool that will spit out normal web components in the end,
native web components but it will make this whole build process a bit easier.
Now let's see how stencil works in detail.
Stencil and that is really important
is not a Javascript framework like Angular and it's not a library like React.
It is a tool that runs on your machine which you will never deploy to a website that is then running
in the web,
it is really just a tool on your machine, like Photoshop is
so to say. It's a compiler for native web components and in the end, what it will spit out is a native
Javascript web component as we wrote it manually
in the first part of this course. Now the idea behind stencil is that stencil.js gives us a way
nicer syntax and a lot of convenience features which we can use to write web components in a more convenient
and error safe way using Javascript and also Typescript,
I'll come back to what Typescript is in a second
in case you don't know that, it is basically something building up on Javascript and in the end, stencil
will then compile that code down to native Javascript web components.
So we don't need to ship any extra library to make these components work in the browser,
it will be the same type of component we build manually, just now being built in a bit of a more convenient
way
and with the additional feature of adding all polyfills that might be required in a browser automatically
so that deploying our web components becomes even easier.
Now what is Typescript? Typescript is a superset to Javascript which means it builds up on Javascript.
It simply adds extra features to the Javascript language,
for example decorators, we can use types there, that is the major thing
hence the name. By default
Javascript is a weekly typed language which means when we have a variable, we don't have to define that
this variable may only hold a number or string,
we can have a string in a variable and then later change it to a number and we won't get any error.
Typescript is stricter about that,
we have to be clear about the types we use in a function or in a variable there
but that gives us a lot of safety during development because we get errors when we start using some
variables incorrectly, when we try to multiply some text or anything like that,
such errors are avoided in Typescript and it additionally also gives us features that are part of Javascript
but are actually next generation Javascript features. We can use them in Typescript but in the end, Typescript
will compile to Javascript and if we want to and stencil wants to, we get Javascript code that runs
in older browsers too. So we can use the latest of the latest and still get Javascript code that runs
in older browsers too.