Now this is all great.
Now one thing is missing though, we can't really open or hide our drawer,
right now it's always visible.
Now there are various ways of making sure we can open and hide it, one would be to add a new prop, the
open prop maybe which is a boolean and let's say and this is true or false obviously.
Now we can use such a property outside now as an attribute and how could we use it?
Well we could for example wrap all our content here into a conditional statement to only render this
if this is true.
This also shows you how you can render content conditionally in this JSX syntax, it's easier than
you might think.
I'll simply add a new variable here in the render function, content and by default, this is null,
so no content
but if this is open, so this is a boolean so checking this will, well either see it is true and then go
into the if block or it's false and we'll skip it.
If this is true though, I'll set content equal to what I previously rendered in all cases.
So I'll just copy that and store this in the variable,
you can store JSX code in variables because behind the scenes, this is just normal Javascript code,
just looking a little bit more appealing and easier to work with
and then here, I return the content and the content now either is null or our own JSX code.
So now we don't see anything because by default, we don't have open set to true.
If I interact with my side drawer though and you might need to reload the page for this to work and I
simply add this open attribute and I don't even need to set it to true,
adding it like this already counts as true,
then you see I can see my side drawer.
So this is a nice way of toggling its display state
and this is one possible way of ensuring that we can see it.