So let's dive into the basics about web components then, how they generally work, how we create our own
web components
and for this, we will use vanilla Javascript.
This means no third party libraries, no other packages, just Javascript as it natively runs in the browser,
at least in modern browsers
and I'll come back to how browser support looks like and how we can build web components that run in
a broad variety of browsers
later in the course.
But first of all, let me come back to the question what web components are.
Obviously we already learned that web components are basically our own HTML tags, like my tooltip
here which is not a tag built into the web or built into the browser and that these are basically
HTML tag which we define in Javascript code and which we then can use on our page.
So web components are really as we use them, custom HTML elements but they are made up of three, theoretically
four but three important parts.
The first and the core part that makes up web components, the web components specification set is the
custom HTML elements specification
and since we in the end build custom HTML elements,
this is the core part.
This is essentially a bunch of Javascript functionalities that allow us to define our own HTML tags
and the logic behind them,
so this is a crucial part.
Now you might wonder ok what else could be important if we are talking about creating our own custom
HTML elements.
Well there are two other pieces which are also very important and which are used in that Javascript logic
we write behind our custom HTML element and the first additional set of functions or of features
offered in Javascript that is important related to creating custom elements is the shadow DOM specification.
The shadow DOM specification is all about giving us some features to create our own DOM tree, our own
elements behind that element you could say that are hidden away from the main DOM and I will come
back to that in more detail later where this will become clearer,
so which is in the end just allowing us to define our own HTML tags which are then grouped together
behind our custom HTML tag and which are separated from our main, our normal DOM
and this is especially helpful when we talk about CSS styling because the shadow DOM will allow
us to define CSS styles that only affect our custom element
and even if we style a h1 tag in our custom element, we would not affect other h1 tags on the page
and this will become all clearer once we actually use it and dive deeper into it.
So it's another crucial part when it comes to separating our logic from the rest of the page, you could
say.
The third important specification is about templates and slots,
this is also something we will use in great detail which in the end allows us to define our own HTML structure
which is hidden behind our custom element and which allows us to add some flexible entry points, these
so-called slots that we can then actually populate with information from outside
when we use our custom element and again, this is something which will become clearer later.
So I know that this is all very confusing right now because I'm throwing a lot of interesting words
around, a lot of specifications without explaining in detail what they do because it makes more sense
to gradually build up the knowledge and we will actually start with custom HTML elements before we
add these other features, before we add the shadow DOM and the templates.
Now I also mentioned that there are four specifications that make up the web components spec and the last
specification is about HTML imports,
the idea here was that we can actually import HTML files into HTML files just as we can import
CSS
and script files
but this is actually not a continuous specification because as you will learn in this course, there is
a more elegant way of importing your components and of importing the
HTML inside of your components.
So we will not need this
and indeed it's not continued, it's not added to our browsers and there are no plans to do so.